>> Hello, everyone. Today, my children are going to be presenting
XTSL, a tool we've been working on with a lot of other people for
prototyping MLIR in Python. So my children are PhD students at
the University of Edinburgh, supervised by Tobias Grocer.
And, broadly speaking, our research group does three things. The first is
actually research into compiler technologies. We really like MORA,
and really like doing research on MORA itself. The second thing we do is
open source development with other departments and other universities for
their computing needs. One of the partners that we've been working on
recently is the climate modeling project in Edinburgh, which is kind of
ironic because it's got the least predictable weather of any place I know
of. So we try to make the predictions run faster, things like that.
And we teach a compiling techniques course with about 150 undergrads every
year. So ideally, because of all the MORA research and work that we do,
we'd really like to teach them MLIR. It's got a ton of great ideas.
And we really would like them by the end of the course to know how SSA
works, to know about blocks in regions, dialects, rewrites, things like that.
But in practice, a lot of the questions that we get about practical concerns
about building an industry compiler, things like table gen, CMake, C++ templates.
Completion times are a big problem for undergrads. And that's a problem for us,
because it's not really what we'd like to teach in the course. What we'd like to
teach is the core concepts themselves. And this problem actually extends to our
partners as well, because they don't really want to be writing the industry
and the compiler is either. They might be doing experiments. And some of these
things that make us as compiler engineers, productive, get in the way of some of the
other things that we do. So how do we solve this problem? We have this crazy idea.
Why don't we just re-implement MLIR in Python? Can we take the same great
concepts that we'd like to teach the students and leverage and have it in an
environment that's more familiar for undergrads than C++ and to the researchers
who use quite often Python for their experiments. That's kind of a crazy idea,
right? Who implements a compiler in Python? But we did it. So it's kind of a unicorn
of a compiler, Scotland's national animal here. And it actually works quite well, right?
So here is a small example of something that in MLIR could be done in table gen,
but here it's exactly the same environment as the rest of the compiler, right? It's Python
with type annotations and some of the concepts that we've developed with the
ML as well, things like constraints with some automatic verification kind of built into
the API. And it's similarly extensible. You can add your own custom printing and
passing syntax. You can add custom verification, nice convenience, initializes, things like that.
And we found that both undergrad students and our partners find this much easier to get
started with than the initial hurdle of learning the same kind of infrastructure in MLIR.
Once we have that, we can actually build up MLIR using this Python API. And we found
that quite successful as well for people to get started with who kind of struggle with
the typos that they might introduce in the MLIR directly. Here the IDE gives you
support. If you've missed something, there's auto-completion. It works quite well for our
use cases. One of the things that is possible in XDSL but isn't possible yet in the Python
bindings is things like rewrites. So once again, the users can write a full end-to-end
compiler defining both the operations and the rewrites in the same environment and be quite
productive with that. We also have the full ecosystem of Python tools available for us.
So here there's a screenshot of a Jupyter notebook running fully in your browser in WebAssembly.
So you can just go to a web page and compile the toy tutorial faster than you can get
both the LLVM repo. And that also lowers the barrier to entry quite a lot. So for the
compiling techniques course, we actually have students implement a full compiler from a
small programming language to a risk five assembly that they can then emulate. So that's a full
end-to-end flow without using a Maria at all. But one of the things we definitely didn't want to do
is create a rift between these two frameworks. So we really want the two communities to work
together to make this tool tooling better and actually have these frameworks be used
alongside each other. We really see XDSL as a sort of sidekick to a Maria that lets you be
productive and prototyping some small features before paying the engineering cost to implement
it nicely in efficiency plus pass industrial grade sort of things. Especially for things like
research ideas where you're trying out a lot of things and you really want to fail fast before
committing the full kind of engineering effort. And one of the great features of a Maria is the
textual format that lets us be fully interoperable with a Maria at any stage of the compilation.
So the tutorial notebooks, for example, you can take the toy tutorial, give it to the
MIR version and it compiles down perfectly. It's fully interoperable. And similarly you can have a
flow that might go first to a Maria, then do a compiler pass in Python, transform the
R, give it back to MIR and use all the optimizations that are in that stack basically for free.
So one of the examples of that is a project by a student that we've worked with that uses
XDSL as almost a front end to get started with, right? So you do some optimizations in the
XDSL level and then compile it down to XDS to MIR and get some significant performance improvement
of some existing databases. Next, MIR will tell you a bit more about how the
interoperation might work in practice and into the future.
>> Thank you. So as we mentioned, we kind of have all two frameworks in completely different
languages, different paradigms. So how do we actually connect them together? So you might
have a different, maybe it's this Python binding solution. But in all case, we are
leveraging the text representation of the MIR in our compiler. So by using the exact
same text representation, we can transfer things back and forth from XDSL and MIR.
So you might already think, oh, yeah, we have kind of generic syntax, but still we need
to understand the dialects themselves. So if we pass the single program that just
we still need to understand the dialects, I have to kind of have a meaning of these
things, to be able to manipulate them, for instance. So for that, we are leveraging
as well IIDL, which is kind of a meta-IR to represent dialects, so we can share these
programs back and forth from MIR on XDSL, which result in actually sharing the dialect
definitions themselves. So this allows us by just sharing the textual syntax and one
single dialect to be able to leverage all the dialects we can have in MIR, pass it to
XDSL and use them directly. Similarly, we want to do the same thing from XDSL to MIR
so that people in the MIR, so we can people that want to kind of prototype their things
in Python and then use it in MIR once it's done, they can try to kind of port this thing
a bit easier than it should. We also want to kind of do the translation from ODS as well.
That's something we kind of are working on right now is going from ODS to IIDL and IIDL
to ODS to allow for like kind of a better portability. So you might ask directly
why not using the Python bindings again? And I kind of want to give you three reasons
why we did not do that. The first one, to be honest, is just, it's faster to write it
again. It's faster to rewrite your own framework in Python like it took us like.
The basic starting point was just in a few days we already had something to represent
programs and to do small rewrites on it and doing this with Python bindings is a bit harder
because you need to interact with the kind of C++ infrastructure you have.
So that's kind of one of the reason. The second reason is more an engineer is
a reason. We're working with people that do not want to have a huge dependency of C++.
They don't want to depend on MLIR and they let the M and all of that stuff.
If MLIR was built in Java and then you had a C++ interface on it,
would you have used it in the first place? Or would you think, oh, this is a Java thing,
like we don't really care about this? Well, for a lot of people, this is the case.
They don't really want to use this entire MLIR ecosystem thing because they don't
really understand it. And lastly, the reason is that as we say, we kind of PhD students
who we like to do research and one of the area of research we have is actually
MLIR itself. If you have a thought about, oh, what if we add
Devident types in MLIR? What if we try to reason about immutable data structures in
MLIR? Well, all of these things require us to kind of modify MLIR itself.
And if you ever looked at the MLIR code base and how, like, I have definitions work,
well, it's really hard and it's like really a long time to understand what's going on.
Whereas in all cases, in our XDSF framework, we don't really care about optimizing it.
We just care about having something simple that we can easily understand so we can
reason with it and modify it. So this is why also, for us, having a
standalone project is nice. So how do we maintain compatibility then?
Since we don't use Python bindings, we have reimplementation of things from MLIR.
Well, MLIR is a project that has a lot of comments every single day.
How can we just being a few PhD students, a few research assistants, how can we
actually maintain this and, like, keep track with MLIR?
So for that, I'm using what I like to call kind of the pyramid of needs of the
MLIR compatibility. So first, you have to base the thing you need to handle.
And this is the textual representation and the intermediate representation.
The textual format and the intermediate representation.
So this is like all the generic syntax for operations, having blocks,
regions, SSA value, attribute types, et cetera.
And this is something that changed really, really rarely.
The last big change has been the addition of properties, but before that,
over the last two years, I don't remember any major change in that direction.
Then, since we want to port dialect from one framework to the other, we need to kind of
have the idea dialect both in XDSL and in MLIR.
This, I expected to change a lot in the next few months because we're actually
actively working on it. But I expected to be stabilized at some point such that we
only have kind of monthly change and not even at that point.
So then we want to have those dialect definitions that we need to port from one
to the other. Well, this changed a lot.
This changed weekly even daily sometimes.
Well, for this, we leverage the ideal dialect to be able to generate these,
meaning that we don't have to pay the weekly cost of updating MLIR if we can do
that kind of automatically. And then finally, there is the last thing that,
in our case, we don't really care that much, is being compatible in terms of API.
Having the same functions, having the same functionality.
So, for instance, I include in that case the patterned provider, which we
re-implemented. But then MLIR has a lot of projects, a lot of IDs, MLIR actions,
we have also data flow analysis. In that case, we don't really need to have the
exact same mechanism. We may want to, in that case, we will port it, but there are
so many things that we don't necessarily care about all of them.
So even though if they change almost daily and we have a lot of API changes,
in our case, it's not really important for us.
So this is why maintaining XDSL currently is more in terms of change every month,
rather than a change every week or a change every day.
So, if you think of this, we kind of present this ID in Python.
I know, it's crazy. But some other people might have, or the language is in mind.
We talk with some people that thought about doing it in C#. Why not?
But then you have some people that have, they need a certain language because
this language allows them to express something they cannot ignore the languages.
For instance, if there's a lot of people thinking of writing frontends for MLIR,
a frontend for writing their programs in a specific way, in a nice syntax, with
nice macros, et cetera. Well, you can do that in a language like Racket.
Right now, people are doing this with frontend in Python, not necessarily good,
but if you choose the right language, Racket here, it can be done kind of.
So if people write this side kick ID, like building this framework,
in Racket, that would be useful for them.
Similarly, some people are crazy enough to try to reason about semantics.
So why not using a language that allows you to reason about semantics like clean or
cock, for instance? And then some people are trying to new language,
like this file module thing.
So the idea you need to keep here is that these should not be separated
projects. These should all be connected somehow into kind of a meta framework.
We have kind of MLIR connecting with XDSL, connecting with whatever you could
implement in other languages through textual IR and ideal.
And please, if you do that, use these tools to allow to kind of share these
abstractions between all these frameworks from this meta framework thing.
So we've presented kind of ID in Python, prototyping MLIR and Python.
And hopefully, like for some users, this will be actually really useful even though
for most of us it sounds a bit crazy.
And hopefully some people can try other stuff, can try to experiment on it,
and this allows us to essentially prototype MLIR directly in a better,
I mean, in a language more appropriate to prototype in.
Thanks a lot.
[APPLAUSE]
So does anyone have any questions for Shash and Matih?
You mentioned IRDL as like a solution to kind of share dialects between these two
programs. But I assume that's only about the
direct definitions. And if you want to have things like transformations and
optimizations, then currently those are re-implemented on both sides.
So for now, if we want to use a specific optimization in MLIR, you can always
translate to MLIR and then get it back.
However, there's some people working on PDL on the transform dialects, which are
other ways to share transformation using the textual representation or using
these intermediate representations.
So while for now we're kind of re-implementing things, we can see in a way if we
evolved to more declarative transformations, then we could see them being translated
from one framework to another.
So at some point we might have an MLIR dialect specifically for optimization
logic. And that could be basically the IRDL version for optimizations.
So we have PDL and transform.
Anyone else?
Great. If there's no one else, then I'll next start in 12 minutes.
Oh, OK.
Yes, kind of ironic. You mentioned compile times as a problem with MLIR, and then
you're going to use Python to write your compiler.
So do you have issues that, like, if you have a Python compiler that the
compile times are bad or is just not a problem with prototyping?
Yeah, it's not really been an issue for us so far.
Right. It's not slower enough to be a consent.
Yeah.
So thanks for all this work. It's super interesting.
I have a question. Let's say you're one of your students in VENTIT's
superthing that we would want in MLIR.
How do you envision contributing this back to MLIR?
Because then they haven't been actually exposed to the MLIR open source community.
So that's a good question. So first of all, I mean, we have dialects,
for instance. We hope that we can translate them more easily using
IDL and translation for IDL to ODS. For transformation, that's true.
They would need to be kind of rewritten. But in the same time,
all transformation in Python are not really meant to be as optimized as you
would expect for the MLIR project itself.
So in any way, there's work to be done to port it.
You need to have better data structures or using a different part of the
framework to encode your transformation in a better way.
So for now, we have a story for the dialects, but for the transformation
themselves, maybe with PDL and the transform dialect, it could be better,
but we don't really have that right now.
We also have examples already of people starting to upstream things
that were initially prototyped in HDSL. Like, IITL is kind of an example like that.
And then the immutable data structures is another PhD student in our group,
who's also simply planning to, once they've kind of developed them,
in Python upstream them, so everyone can use them in a MIR itself.
And also, there's also thinking, right now, there's kind of no alternative in Python.
There's like a lot of people that like to write compiler in Python,
like, DSL in the research community, but they're currently writing it in completely
different paradigms. So at least bring it to the same paradigm with the same concept,
kind of make it easier for them.
Anyone else?
Great. So if there's no one else, thanks, Ashram, Matie.
And our next talk starts in 10 minutes. Thanks.
[Applause]